Guide to the Office of Training records, 1865-2002 RG0065
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Office of Training records
1865-2002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington Univeristy. Office of Training
RG0065
3 Linear Feet
Collection includes slides, correspondence, manuals, and course registration information.
Restrictions on Access
Series 1 is closed to research for 25 years from the date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from Office of Training.
Historical Note
Employee Training and Development offers a wide variety of courses and seminars that help employees of the University enhance their job skills. Workshops include topics such as customer service, effective writing, time management, general office skills, employee orientation, workshops for new managers.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in the collection include slides, correspondence, manuals, and course registration. The material dates from 1865-2002. Note: Not all series are processed. Ask staff for assistance.
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: Medical Center, two series titled Images of campus life, Courses, and Professional development records.
Black-and-white slides; Employees; Washington (D.C.); Training; Color slides; George Washington University
- Medical Center, RG0065 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains user manuals. These manuals are from the Medical Center.
  - Generic Portion - User Manual; Medical Records Unit Specific Users Manual, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Includes MPI, Incomplete Charts, Record Abstracting, Standard Screen Features, Computer Terminology
  - Generic Portion - User Manual, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Department of Nursing Unit Specific Users Manual [1/3], undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes: Census inquiry, physician inquiry, transfer/pass function, discharge functions, enter/update patient summary profiles
  - Lists of Illustrations [1/2], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Five Account access Methods, Billing summaries, display guarantor data, display third parties, display associated case, account notes, transactions
  - Lists of Illustrations [2/2], undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial Unit Specific Portion Users Manual, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes: Overview, display account information, PFAC verification, insurance information, billing, cash applications, follow up, special collections
  - Department of Nursing Specific Users Manual [2/3], undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes: Census Inquiry, Physician Inquiry, Transfer/Pass Function, Discharge Functions, Enter/Update Patient Summary Profiles
  - Department of Nursing Specific Users Manual [3/3], undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Inquiry by In-House Patient Name Display Emergency Unit Census, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Services Unit Specific Users Manual, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes: Follow-up, Special Collection
  - General Portion Users Manual, Medical Records Unit Specific Users Manual, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes: Master Patient Index, Incomplete Charts, Record Abstracting, Standard Screen Features
  - Admitting Unit Specific Users Manual; Radiation Oncology Unit Specific Users Manual; Emergency Unit Specific Users Manual [1/3], undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes: (Inpatient Pre-admission, Inpatient Newborn Admission, Outpatient Pre-registration, Outpatient Registration, Recurring Outpatient, Transfer, Discharge, Conversion, Census and Inquiry, Name Change/Add Alias); (MPI Standard Screen Features, Recurring Outpatient Registration, Discharge Recurring Outpatient, Inquiry by Inhouse Patient Name, Inquiry by Physician, Name Change/Add Alias); (Emergency Unit Registration, Discharge Functions, Name Change/Add Alias, Census Functions, Reprint Record Plate, Reregister Discharge in Error)
  - Inquiry by Inhouse Patient Name Display Emergency Unit Census [1/2], undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Five Account Access Methods, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Billing Summaries, Display Guarantor Data, Display Third Parties, Display Associated Case, Account Notes, Transactions
  - Financial Services Unit Specific Users Manual, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Follow-up, Special Collections
  - Admitting Unit Specific Users Manual; Radiation Oncology Unit Specific Users Manual; Emergency Unit Specific Users Manual [2/3], undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Admitting Unit Specific Users Manual; Radiation Oncology Unit Specific Users Manual; Emergency Unit Specific Users Manual [3/3], undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Inquiry by Inhouse Patient Name Display Emergency Unit Census [2/2], undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Images of campus life, 1963; RG0065 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains slides. These 217 slides include images of The George Washington University Hospital, staff, and faculty.
  - Hospital building, hospital kitchen, administrative staff, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hospital building, patients, administrative staff, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative staff, janitorial staff, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Names of administrative staff include: Elmer Kayser, W.M. P. Smith, Dean Linton, Mr. Houser, Provost Colclough, Pres. Carroll, Dr. Latimer, Dr. Woodruff Kramer, Dr. Kirkbride, Mr. Herzog, Mrs. Borden
- Courses, 1979-1986; RG0065 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains correspondence and course registration. The material covers the years 1979-86.
- Images of campus life, 1865-1995; RG0065 Series 4; 1.0 Linear foot (Box 2, Box 1)
  This series contains approximately 1,000 slides. Subjects include campus buildings, faculty, students, and staff. These slides were used for new employee orientations, and range in date from 1865-1995.
  - Faculty and Staff, 1975 ca.-1985 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Faculty and Staff, including James Horton, Marcus Cunliffe, Administrative personnel. Convocation and registration scenes.
  - Campus scenes, 1920-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Campus scenes: computer labs, students in class. Old university seals, buildings, including old Preparatory School, Tin Tabernacle (ca. 1924), University Yard, Washington Monument under construction.
  - Campus Buildings, 1865 ca.-1990 ca. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Campus Buildings including Gelman library, law school, medical buildings, construction scenes, aerial photos of campus, Fords Theater (ca. 1865).
  - Hospital Scenes, 1896-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Hospital Scenes, gross anatomy class (ca. 1896), operating rooms (ca. 1950s), rehab, rooms, medical students and staff. Drawings of campus buildings.
  - Buildings and people, 1825 ca.-1965 ca. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Drawings of buildings, College Hill (ca. 1821), Capital building. Civil war photos, Carver Barracks, general hospital, Columbian College building (ca. 1865). Prominent people, William Staughton, Thomas Sewall, Walter Reed, Riley, Glasscock, President Coolidge, President Kennedy, President Truman.
  - Campus scenes and people, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Approximately 625 slides used to train new employees, housed in a three-ring binder. Subjects include images used for brochures, Student Accounts Office, Admissions Office, GW seal, aerial views from roof tops, students moving in to dorms, cupola of Corcoran Hall, metro station, university yard, Gelman Library, research, mailroom, computer room, Engineering Dept., Academic Center, Munson Hall, Rice Hall office 5th floor, professors office, banners, Lisner Auditorium, J Street in Marvin Center, clock by Gelman Library, bookstore, classroom scenes.
- Professional development records, 1980-2002; RG0065 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains manuals, pamphlets, schedules, catalogs, correspondence, and flyers. They range in date from 1980 to 2002. They concern strategies for supervision, discipline in the work environment, workshops, development opportunities, seminars, employee performance appraisal, staff development, quality management, and interviewing.
  - Personnel Services, Department of Training Division Program, 01/1980-06/1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Personnel Services, Department of Training Division Program Discipline in the Work Environment, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Services, Department of Training Division Program Strategies for Supervision, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Quality Management Resources Workshops, 09/1994-05/13/2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)